Hello, everyone, and welcome
to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine, and
today we're going to buy
some food at a store for
basically bread, right, Marco?
That's right, today we're going
to a bakery, so this is basically a
shop where they sell bread and
different types of bread, actually.
That's right, so we're going
to learn all about these
different kinds of bread. Let's
take a listen to our dialogue.
Welcome to Al's Bakery. What can I get you?
Hi, let me get a
dozen croissants, four
blueberry muffins and a
loaf of sourdough bread.
Sure.
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
No, that's okay.
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
Oh, we're out at the moment.
May I suggest some rye bread?
Sure, that sounds good.
Do you have any cakes?
We have various birthday cakes
and also some ice cream cakes.
I'll just take a cheesecake.
Will that be all? Yes.
The total is $43.20.
All right, we're back, so now let's take a
look at some vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
In language takeaway today we
have many different kinds of bread.
The first kind actually
comes to English
from the French language.
We have croissants.
As you say, this is a type of bread
that comes from France, I guess.
That's right. It's
really delicious.
It's buttery and flaky and
it's in the shape of a crescent.
So it's like a curve, like a sea.
It kind of looks like also horns
because it's got two little...
It's got a horn on each side.
It does. It does. Many people like
to eat this for breakfast and France,
but you can find it everywhere
in America at cafes and bakeries.
Okay, very good. So those are croissants.
And now we're also
buying blueberry muffins.
Okay, muffins are a delicious baked good.
Blueberry muffins are at the flavor, so
we can also have strawberry or orange.
But in this case, a muffin is
kind of like a sweet baked good.
It's round. It's kind of
like a cake, like a little cake.
It is like a little cake.
The top is bigger than the bottom.
You have some paper to hold on to. And the
top is round and maybe a little bit hard.
Okay, very good. So those are muffins.
We'll post pictures of these on the
site so you can see what they look like.
But moving on now, we have a type of bread.
This is a sourdough bread.
All right, so there are many, many,
many different kinds of breads.
But sourdough is very unique because the
flavor is a little bit sour. It's strong.
So dough is the substance or
what you use to make bread, right?
Or before bread is baked.
That's right. So before you make
bread, it's kind of like a liquid.
You have some milk or
water that you mix with flour.
So you have to hold in a bowl or a cup.
And after you bake it, it becomes hard.
So dough is when it's
soft and like a liquid.
Right.
You've seen it when they're making bread.
It looks like a paste sometimes
and then it becomes hard.
Or when they're making
pizzas, that's called dough.
And sour, obviously
because it has that flavor
that you said, a very
strong sour flavor.
That's right.
And a different kind of bread that
we might find is whole wheat bread.
Okay, now this is like the healthy choice.
Yes, it's normally the healthy choice.
That's because the flour that we
put in the dough is whole wheat flour.
Yes, it's a little
bit healthier.
It's usually a little bit
darker than white flour.
So it'll be brown.
So yeah, it's basically the brown bread.
I think if you've noticed when you
go to the store and you can get bread,
you'll find one that
looks white in the inside.
And this one actually
looks brown on the inside.
That's right.
And an even more brown colored
bread and even black is rye bread.
So what is rye?
Rye is another kind of
grain, and when you bake
this rye bread, it has
a very strong flavor.
And it's very, very dark, almost black.
It's actually my favorite kind of bread.
So what does it taste like?
Or what's the difference between
whole wheat bread and rye bread?
Rye bread is much heavier.
It has a stronger flavor.
Whole wheat bread is lighter.
Okay, very good.
So obviously it's
maybe a little bit difficult
to understand the
differences between the breads,
but we'll post pictures on
the site so you can see them.
And also, well, you can,
you have to go out to the
bakery and try them so
you can taste the difference.
That's right.
All right.
So now let's move on to
language takeaway part two and talk
about a little bit more of the
other vocab found in this lesson.
Welcome to Al's Bakery.
What can I get you?
Hi, let me get a
dozen croissants, four
blueberry muffins and a
loaf of sourdough bread.
Sure.
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
No, that's okay.
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
Oh, we're out at the moment.
May I suggest some rye bread?
Sure, that sounds good.
Do you have any cakes?
We have various birthday cakes
and also some ice cream cakes.
I'll just take a cheesecake.
Will that be all?
Yes.
Your total is $43.20.
So when you want to go buy
some bread or some baked
goods, you have to know
how to count those goods.
So today we have a couple of
words to help you count bread.
The first one we have is dozen.
That's right.
So for croissants, as you
can see, it's a countable noun.
And so when you ask for a dozen
croissants, you're asking for 12.
That's right.
So in English, the word dozen means 12.
You can buy a dozen eggs or in this
case dozen blueberry muffins maybe.
Okay.
So it's a very popular term.
A dozen or a half a dozen.
Sometimes people just buy six.
That's right.
So half a dozen is six.
A whole dozen, to say dozen, is 12.
You can also have something
special called a baker's dozen.
Yes, I've heard about this.
What is a baker's dozen?
Well, a baker's dozen
is basically a present.
The baker gives you.
So you buy 12, maybe 12 croissants.
And the baker gives you one more.
That's a good 13.
Yes.
A baker's dozen is 13.
But do you ask for a baker's dozen?
Or does the baker say, I'm going
to give you the baker's dozen?
I don't think I've ever asked for it.
I think when I've bought bagels and
they give me, I say, I want a dozen bagels.
They give me a baker's dozen.
They give me 13.
Oh, okay.
So when you're buying bread.
Now, obviously you don't really
buy a dozen sourdough breads.
You buy a dozen loaves of sourdough bread.
So the countable noun
here is a loaf of bread.
One loaf, two loaves.
Now this is very interesting
because in English,
we don't have that many
counting words, measure words.
Right.
But for bread, we do
actually have this special word.
So you can say, I would like
two loaves of sourdough bread.
Okay.
And the loaf or loaves in
the plural, what is it exactly?
It's one big piece.
So for example, you have
maybe one little piece of bread.
It's called a slice.
That's what you eat.
But when you buy the bread, you
have many, many, many slices together.
So you cut the bread.
That's called a loaf.
Very good.
So actually this is the reason why the
baker or the person attending the shop
asked if he would like
to have the loaf sliced.
Would you like the loaf sliced?
That means would you like us to
cut pieces of bread from this loaf?
Because sliced bread is how you eat it.
Right.
Exactly.
You don't really take a whole loaf
of bread and start eating it like that.
And animal, no, you cut it into slices.
And so sliced bread, we say, is one option.
You can also have unsliced, which means
when you go home, you cut it yourself.
So this is a very particular word as well.
Because you have the adjective
to have sliced bread, right?
You also have the verb to slice the bread.
That means to cut it into slices.
And of course, you have
the noun slices of bread.
So you have the individual pieces.
It can be a verb and adjective and a noun.
That's right.
So it can be a little confusing.
But I recommend you
all check out the website
and practice a little bit
in the comment section.
All right.
Good.
So let's take a listen to
the dialogue one last time.
Welcome to Al's Bakery.
What can I get you?
Hi.
Let me get a dozen croissants, four blueberry
muffins and a loaf of sourdough bread.
Sure.
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
No.
That's OK.
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
Oh, we're out at the moment.
May I suggest some rye bread?
Sure.
That sounds good.
Do you have any cakes?
We have various birthday cakes
and also some ice cream cakes.
I'll just take a cheesecake.
Will that be all?
Yes.
Your total is $43.20.
All right.
So speaking about breads now,
there is some particular ingredients
that we don't mention
in the dialogue obviously.
But they're worth mentioning.
What is the one main
characteristic that most breads have?
East.
That's right.
Y E A S T yeast.
And yeast is actually alive.
It's an animal.
It's like a bacteria.
That's right.
And so you wonder why are some breads
flat and why are some breads big poofy?
Large.
Well, yeast is why.
Not sure.
Basically, you can't have a big
poofy bread, a big large tall bread.
Unless you have this yeast.
So yeast is what makes the bread rise.
Yes.
And we also mentioned
flour, which is basically just
a powder made out of
some type of grain, usually.
Yeah.
Usually it's made out of wheat.
Obviously, whole wheat is a
little bit different from the white
flour, which would be a
different processed wheat.
But we also have different things
that you can even have rice flour.
Right, corn flour.
Corn flour.
Corn bread would be, of course,
yellow, because corn is yellow.
Now, so you can hear that we
say the word flour, like a rose
is a flour, but it's
actually spelled different.
F L O U R flour.
So there's two different things.
There's flowers in your garden.
And there's flour, F L O U R, which
is something you can cook with.
That's right.
These are called homophones.
So they basically have the same
pronunciation, but very different spellings.
And very different meanings.
Exactly.
So a very interesting lesson for us today.
Go out, get some bread.
Try some of these if
you have them available.
But also, come to the
questions and comments
section and tell us about
maybe your local bread.
I know that many countries around the
world have very specific types of bread.
That's right.
Right.
Some names down for us.
Send us your pictures and
we'll see you on the website.
All right.
Bye, guys.
Bye.